Guide to the Peter Newell Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Peter Newell: Visual Materials, 1879-1923; Series II; 295.1; (176 boxes) + 37 oil paintings
  - UNIDENTIFIED OR UNPUBLISHED DRAWINGS
    - Headpieces and Covers
      - Headpieces for stories, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1829-1835)
      - "Lippincott's Select Novels" covers, ca. 1890 (Box 142, Folder 1836-1837)
      - Unidentified cover, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1838)
    - Story Illustrations
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 143, Folder 1839-1858)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 144, Folder 1859-1876)
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 1888-1898)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 147, Folder 1899-1907)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 148, Folder 1908-1917)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 1918-1923)
    - Other Drawings and Sketches
      - "Granny's Clothespins", 1891 (Box 150, Folder 1924-1925)
      - "The Witch's Clothespins", ca. 1891 (Box 150, Folder 1926)
      - "The Telephone", 1891 (Box 150, Folder 1927-1928)
      - "The Watercolorist", 1891 (Box 150, Folder 1929-1931)
      - Drawings, 1887-90 (Box 151, Folder 1932-1935)
      - Seasonal drawings with poems, ca. 1905 (Box 151, Folder 1936-1939)
      - Military men with movable eyes, ca. 1918 (Box 151, Folder 1940)
      - Illustrations for fables, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 1941-1947)
      - Illustrations for "Little Monologues", n.d. (Box 152, Folder 1948-1949)
      - Illustrated poems, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 1950-1963)
      - Sand drawings (drawings with sand affixed) (Box 152, Folder 1964-1965)
      - Animal sketches, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 1966-1970)
      - Drawings, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 1971-1989)
  - TOYS AND NOVELTIES
    Contains two sketches for toys and several folded paper action pieces, some apparently intended for corporate advertising. Media include ink, pencil, gouache and watercolor.
    - Designs for whirling toys (2), ca. 1922 (Box 154, Folder 1990)
    - Bend-back figures (7), ca. 1910 (Box 154, Folder 1991)
    - Doorway pop-up figures (4), ca. 1910 (Box 154, Folder 1992)
    - Moving pictures (11), ca. 1910 (Box 154, Folder 1993)
    - Pop-up figures (4), ca. 1910 (Box 154, Folder 1994)
    - Talking figures (5), ca. 1910 (Box 154, Folder 1995)
    - View-through figures (6), ca. 1910 (Box 154, Folder 1996)
    - Miscellaneous figures (6), ca. 1910, 1915 (Box 154, Folder 1997)
    - Designs for clothing decorations, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 1998)
  - FINE ART
    The subseries consists of Peter Newell's personal artwork and is arranged by: Sketches, Sketchbooks and Student Work; Portraits and Self-Portraits: Watercolor Paintings and Wash Drawings; Oil Paintings; and Other Works on Paper.
    - Sketches, Sketchbooks and Student Work
      This section contains primarily figure and landscape drawings made during Newell's student days and sketching trips at home and abroad. Two of the groups of figure drawings are dated and were probably made while he was at the Art Students League; the remainder of the figure drawings appear to date from the same periods.
      - Character studies from sketchbook, ca. 1880 (Box 154, Folder 1999)
      - Sketchbook of figure drawings, 1883 (Box 154, Folder 2000)
      - Sketchbook from European tour, 1897 (Box 154, Folder 2001)
      - Sketchbooks from Paris, France (3); one with sketches by Alfred Z. Baker and one with juvenile drawings and inscriptions by Clendenon Newell, 1900 (Box 154, Folder 2002)
      - Sketchbook with character studies, rural scenes and self-portrait, 1920 (Box 154, Folder 2003)
      - Character studies (10 sheets), n.d. (Box 154, Folder 2004)
      - Figure studies (18 in 10 folders), 1883 (Box 155, Folder 2005-2014)
      - Figure studies, 1891 (Box 155, Folder 2015-2031)
      - Figure studies of women, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2032-2045)
      - Figure studies of men, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2046-2059)
      - Figure drawing class (Art Students League?), ca. 1891
        See: Oversize, Folder 3350
      - Caricature of Mack Pinckly, 1880 (Box 157, Folder 2060)
      - Illinois sketch, 1883 Feb (Box 157, Folder 2061)
      - Indiana sketches, 1883 Mar (Box 157, Folder 2062-2063)
      - New York sketches, 1883 Mar (Box 157, Folder 2064-2066)
      - Caricature of a Springfield man, ca. 1884 (Box 157, Folder 2067)
      - Sketch, 1886 (Box 157, Folder 2068)
      - Colorado (?) sketches, ca. 1888 (Box 157, Folder 2069-2071)
      - Caricature of a photographer, 1891 (Box 157, Folder 2072)
      - Mr. Cottrel of Philadelphia, 1921 (Box 157, Folder 2073)
      - Caricature of a sportsman?, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 2074)
      - Figure studies, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 2075-2078)
      - Still life and landscape studies (Box 157, Folder 2079-2083)
    - Portraits and Self-Portraits
      - Family Members
        - Baker, Alfred (Tony) Z., Jr., ca. 1908-10 (Box 158, Folder 2084-2086)
        - Gordon, Helen Newell Baker, 1887-89 (Box 158, Folder 2087-2089)
        - Gordon, Helen Newell Baker, ca. 1910 (Box 158, Folder 2090)
        - Gordon, Helen Newell and Josephine Newell McCormick, ca. 1890-93 (Box 159, Folder 2091-2092)
        - Nankivel, Amanda Newell, 1897 Jan 5 (Box 159, Folder 2093)
        - Newell, Leona, ca. 1895 (Box 159, Folder 2094)
        - Newell, Leona, ca. 1920 (Box 159, Folder 2095)
      - Self-Portraits
        See also: Box 187, Folder 2317
        - Caricature, ca. 1880 (Box 160, Folder 2096)
        - For business card, 1884 (Box 160, Folder 2097)
        - Caricature with Leona, ca. 1885 (Box 160, Folder 2098)
        - In Paris, 1897 (Box 160, Folder 2099)
        - In Paris, 1900 (Box 160, Folder 2100)
        - For Hayden Carruth, ca. 1901 (Box 160, Folder 2101-2102)
        - Profile portrait, 1913 (Box 160, Folder 2103)
        - Self-portrait signature, ca. 1908 (Box 161, Folder 2104)
        - Self-portrait signatures (2), ca. 1908 (Box 161, Folder 2105)
        - Sketches and drawings (Box 161, Folder 2106-2113)
      - Leonia residents
        - Diehl, Jennie, 1894 Nov 6 (Box 162, Folder 2114)
        - Eaton, Mrs., n.d. (Box 162, Folder 2115)
        - Fox, Julia, n.d. (Box 162, Folder 2116)
        - Gausman, Roy, 1897 Jan 19 (Box 162, Folder 2117)
        - Gismond, Corporal A. C., ca. 1917 (Box 162, Folder 2118)
        - Gregg, Gertrude, n.d. (Box 163, Folder 2119)
        - Gregg, Gertrude, 1894 Nov 13 (Box 163, Folder 2120)
        - Gregg, Gertrude, 1895 Feb 12 (Box 163, Folder 2121)
        - Grinslade, Leah, n.d. (Box 163, Folder 2122)
        - Kittridge, Mrs., n.d. (Box 163, Folder 2123)
        - Ludwig, Alexis, 1894 Feb 2 (Box 163, Folder 2124)
        - Norton, Jeannette Young, n.d. (Box 163, Folder 2125)
        - Perrine, Van Dearing, 1894 Mar 30 (Box 164, Folder 2126)
        - Peters, George, n.d. (Box 164, Folder 2127)
        - Schilling, Alexander (Box 164, Folder 2128)
        - Stagg, Anna, 1900 Dec 16 (Box 164, Folder 2129)
        - Whitley, Abram, n.d. (Box 164, Folder 2130)
        - Yalden, J. Ernest G., n.d. (Box 164, Folder 2131)
        - Unidentified, n.d., 1894 (Box 164, Folder 2132-2135)
    - Watercolor Paintings and Wash Drawings
      The quantity of Newell's leisure time work precludes an itemized listing. The paintings have been arranged by date and size, with undated works at the end.
      - Kansas scenes, 1887 (Box 165, Folder 2136-2137)
      - Colorado scenes, 1888 (Box 165, Folder 2138-2141)
      - Rural scenes, 1888 (Box 165, Folder 2142-2143)
      - Illinois scenes, 1888-89 (Box 166, Folder 2144-2149)
      - Rural scene, framed, 1889 Jul (Box 167, Folder 2150)
      - Still life, 1891 (Box 168, Folder 2151)
      - Rural scenes, 1891 (Box 168, Folder 2152-2155)
      - Rural scene, 1894 (Box 168, Folder 2156)
      - Rural scenes, 1895 (Box 168, Folder 2157-2158)
      - Rural scenes, 1896 (Box 168, Folder 2159-2162)
      - Rural scene, framed, 1895 (Box 169, Folder 2163)
      - Rural scenes (2), 1896
        See: Oversize, Folders 3351-3352
      - Rural scenes, 1896 (Box 170, Folder 2164-2165)
      - New Jersey scene, framed, 1897 Apr 30 (Box 170, Folder 2166)
      - French scenes, 1897 (Box 170, Folder 2167-2170)
      - French and Dutch scenes, 1897 (Box 171, Folder 2171-2178)
      - Dutch scenes, framed, 1897 Sep (Box 172, Folder 2179-2180)
      - [Number not used] (Box 173)
      - Gloucester, MA, scenes, 1899 (Box 174, Folder 2181-2187)
      - Gloucester, MA, scene, framed, [1899] (Box 175, Folder 2188)
      - Nautical scene, 1900 (Box 176, Folder 2189)
      - Rural scenes, 1907 Aug (Box 176, Folder 2190-2191)
      - Rural scene, 1909 Aug (Box 176, Folder 2192)
      - Connecticut scenes, 1921 (Box 176, Folder 2193-2197)
      - Rural scenes, n.d. (Box 177, Folder 2198-2207)
      - Farm scenes, n.d. (Box 178, Folder 2208-2219)
      - Rural and urban scenes (Box 179, Folder 2220-2228)
      - Rural and farm scenes (Box 180, Folder 2229-2240)
      - Rural scenes, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 2241-2242)
      - Waterside scenes, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 2243-2246)
      - Italian (?) scene, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 2247)
    - Other Works on Paper
      - Christmas/New Year greeting, 1883 (Box 182, Folder 2248)
      - Christmas greetings, n.d. (Box 182, Folder 2249-2250)
      - [Boy at waters edge], monotype, ca. 1914 (Box 182, Folder 2251)
      - Rabbit for sale sign, n.d. (Box 182, Folder 2252)
      - Cut-out silhouette heads (11) from Leonia chalk talk, n.d. (Box 182, Folder 2253-2257)
    - Oil Paintings
      Listed in chronological order within two groups, with support and size. Many of the paintings are unsigned and are unframed unless noted. Paintings listed in the first group are on unstretched canvas fragments and are housed in boxes stored with Series II, while those on board, on stretchers or in frames are held in the library's art storage area. The latter group has the code "art" and the folder number is used as a unique identification number only.
      - [Three boys at pond] on unstretched canvas, 10-1/4 x 15 in., 1888 (Box 183, Folder 2258)
      - Portrait of Clendenon Newell on unstretched and folded canvas, 14 x 12 in. (image), ca. 1910 (Box 183, Folder 2259)
      - Portrait of a Baby (Helen Newell?) on canvas fragment, 9 x 8-1/4 in., n.d. (Box 183, Folder 2260)
      - [Ashcraft farm, Malta, IL] on canvas fragment, 10-3/4 x 9-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 183, Folder 2261)
      - [Boy with hat looking up] on canvas fragment, 9-3/4 x 6-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 184, Folder 2262)
      - [Farm scene] on canvas fragment, 12-1/2 x 12 in., n.d. (Box 184, Folder 2263)
      - [Figure with animal in landscape] on canvas fragment, 15 x 11-1/2 in. (Box 184, Folder 2264)
      - [Landscape from high hill] on canvas mounted on board, 13-1/4 x 11 in. (Box 184, Folder 2265)
      - [Man on hillside] on unstretched canvas, 12 x 14 in., n.d. (Box 185, Folder 2266)
      - [Rural scene with pasture, pond and trees] on canvas fragment, 10-1/2 x 12-1/2 in. (Box 185, Folder 2267)
      - [Rural scene with stream and fence] on canvas fragment, 12-3/4 x 13-1/2 in. (Box 185, Folder 2268)
      - [Rural scene with trees] on canvas fragment, 12-1/2 x 10 in., n.d. (Box 185, Folder 2269)
      - [Small child, reaching up] on canvas fragment, 9-1/4 x 6-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 185, Folder 2270)
      - [Landscape] on panel (cigar box top), 4-1/4 x 7 in. (Box 186, Folder 2271)
      - [Still life with book, comb, brush and bottle] on canvas fragment, 10-3/4 x 13 in. (Box 186, Folder 2272)
      - [Two children in a field] on canvas fragment, 11 x 13-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 186, Folder 2273)
      - [Waterfall] on canvas fragment, 15 x 12-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 186, Folder 2274)
      - [White barn] on canvas fragment, 13 x 16-1/4 in., n.d. (Box 186, Folder 2275)
      - "The Prodigal Son" on canvas, 27-5/8 x 36 in; framed, ca. 1883 (Box art, Folder 2276)
      - [Child pulling dog on leash] on canvas, 18 x 22 in., 1887 (Box art, Folder 2277)
      - [Hay stacks, waterside] on canvas, 14 x 18 in., 1894 Aug 28 (Box art, Folder 2278)
      - [Seaside scene] on canvas, 10 x 14 in., 1896 (Box art, Folder 2279)
      - [Rear view of Newell house, Leonia] on board, 20 x 15-1/2 in., ca. 1920 (Box art, Folder 2280)
      - The Camping Ground on board, 14 x 18 in.; framed, 1920 (Box art, Folder 2281)
      - The Brook on board, 15 x 19 in.; exhibition label on verso for "1924 Exhibition", 1921 (Box art, Folder 2282)
      - In the Berkshires on board, 20 x 22-1/2 in.; framed, 1921 (Box art, Folder 2283)
      - [Farmer at barn door] on board, 18-1/2 x 20 in., 1921 (Box art, Folder 2284)
      - [Hay wagon crossing bridge] on board, 14 x 16-1/2 in.; framed, 1921 (Box art, Folder 2285)
      - [Man at camp, girl in blue on porch] on board, 15 x 20 in., 1921 (Box art, Folder 2286)
      - [Man walking next to cornfield before high hill] on board, 18-1/2 x 14 in., 1921 (Box art, Folder 2287)
      - [Old woman carrying sticks] on board, 16 x 14-1/2 in.; framed, 1921 (Box art, Folder 2288)
      - [Rural scene, man with horse] on board, 14-3/4 x 12 in., 1921 (Box art, Folder 2289 ptg)
      - The Deep Woods on board, 16 x 20 in.; Salmagundi Club exhibition label on verso and sticker lower left; also label on verso for "1924 Exhibition"; in carved and painted frame made by Newell), 1922 (Box art, Folder 2290)
      - The Farm on board, 20 x 16 in.; exhibition sticker lower left (probably from Salmagundi Club), 1922 (Box art, Folder 2291)
      - The Orchard on board, 16 x 20; Salmagundi Club exhibition tag on verso and sticker on lower left, 1922 (Box 2292 (Art))
      - [Boy driving sheep along hillside] on board, 16 x 20 in., 1922 (Box art, Folder 2293)
      - [Cows and windmill] on board, 14-1/4 x 13-1/4 in.; label on verso from "1924 Exhibition" and exhibition sticker lower left; in carved and painted frame made by Newell), ca. 1922 (Box art, Folder 2294)
      - [Elderly couple on porch with cat] on board, 20 x 16 in., 1922 (Box art, Folder 2295)
      - [Farmer with cow and poultry] on board, 16 x 20 in., 1922 (Box art, Folder 2296)
      - [Girl in blue wading in river] on board, 20 x 16 in., 1922 (Box art, Folder 2297)
      - [Girl with teddy bear on lawn] on board, 24 x 18 in., ca. 1922 (Box art, Folder 2298)
      - [Three children before shed and house, woman on porch] on board, 16 x 20 in., 1922 (Box art, Folder 2299)
      - The Balloon Ascension on board, 20 x 16 in.; Salmagundi Club exhibition label on verso dated Oct 25, 1923, ca. 1923 (Box art, Folder 2300)
      - [Boy at gate with dog] on canvas, 32 x 26; framed, n.d. (Box art, Folder 2301)
      - [Industrial scene in winter] on board, 10-1/4 x 14-1/2 in. (Box art, Folder 2302)
      - [Landscape with pond] (torn) on canvas, 12 x 14 in. (Box art, Folder 2303)
      - [Landscape with road and fence] on board, 9 x 12 in. (Box 186, Folder 2304)
      - [Portrait of a woman (Marion Ashcraft?)] on canvas, 20 x 16 in., n.d. (Box art, Folder 2305)
      - [River scene with factories in background] on board, 10-1/2 x 14-1/2 in. (Box art, Folder 2306)
      - [Rural scene with child and dog] on canvas board, 9-3/4 x 16 in. (Box art, Folder 2307)
      - [Rural scene with haystack] on board, 9 x 10-1/4 in., n.d. (Box art, Folder 2308)
      - [Two children] on canvas, 17 x 14 in., n.d. (Box art, Folder 2309)
      - [Urban scene] on board, 5-3/4 x 8 in., n.d. (Box art, Folder 2310)
      - [Woman and child walking toward barn] on canvas, 20 x 16 in. (Box art, Folder 2311)
      - [Woman at door of rural cabin] on canvas over board, 20 x 16 in., n.d. (Box art, Folder 2312)
  - THREE-DIMENSIONAL OBJECTS
    The subseries contains objects made by Peter Newell: Relief Carvings; Sculpture; and Toys and Models. Also here are Family Memorabilia, items that were owned and used by Newell and his family.
    - Relief Carvings
      Media include watercolor, gouache and pencil on carved wood.
      - "Both of the same mind" 6 x 7-1/2 in. (Box 187, Folder 2313)
        (See also a Newell comic in Harper's Young People, November 4, 1890)
      - [Nobleman with shield] with applied metal, 6-1/2 x 3-1/4 in. signed on verso: Peter Newell April 1907, 1907 Apr (Box 187, Folder 2314)
      - [Portrait of a woman] with applied plaster, 6-1/2 x 4-1/8 in. signed on verso: "Peter Newell April 1907", 1907 Apr (Box 187, Folder 2315)
      - Portrait of David ("Bud") Talmage 9-1/2 x 5 in.; incised lower right: "Peter Newell" (Box 187, Folder 2316)
        See also: Series VIII, Box 219, Folder 3034
      - Self-portrait 10 x 7-3/4 in.; inscribed upper left: "To Mr. Charles Battell Loomis Faithfully yours, Peter Newell", ca. 1907 (Box 187, Folder 2317)
    - Sculpture
      All but tree fungus are carved and painted wood. Folder numbers are used as unique identification numbers only.
      - [Head of a native], n.d. (Box 187, Folder 2318)
      - [Old man with book, hat and umbrella] 9-1/2 in. high; incised on base: "Peter Newell-1917" (Box 187, Folder 2319)
      - [Tree fungus with bird], n.d. (Box 187, Folder 2320)
      - The Wood Family
        See also: Series I, Box 13, Folder 268; and Oversize, Box 245, Folders 3367-3368
        - [Man with boater] 2-1/4 in. high, ca. 1911 (Box 187, Folder 2321)
        - [Woman with white bow] 2-1/4 in. high, ca. 1911 (Box 187, Folder 2322)
        - [Young boy with blue bow] 2-1/8 in. high; inscribed on base: "To Tony from Grandpa Aug 10, 1911" (Box 187, Folder 2323)
    - Toys and Models
      - A series of action toys designed by Newell, some of which were put into production and several of which received patents. The figures described as "by Diamond Jim" were manufactured by the Diamond Toy Company, while the others are models carved and painted by Newell. Folder numbers are used as unique identification numbers only.
        See also: Series I, Box 8, Folders 133-137
      - "The Doughboy and the Boch", ca. 1920 (Box 188, Folder 2324)
      - "The early bird catches the worm," by Diamond Jim, ca. 1921 (Box 188, Folder 2325)
      - [A Fisherman], ca. 1920 (Box 188, Folder 2326)
      - [Girl holding flower], ca. 1920 (Box 189, Folder 2327)
      - [Girl smelling flower], ca. 1920 (Box 189, Folder 2328)
      - [Girl with pumpkin] (pull toy), ca. 1921 (Box 189, Folder 2329)
      - Heads, broken off from unknown toys, n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2330-2331)
      - [Horse "phonograph" toy] (broken), n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2332-2333)
      - [Jumping jack] (head broken off), n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2334)
      - "The Kiddy Speller," by Diamond Jim, ca. 1921 (Box 190, Folder 2335)
      - [Man and dog], ca. 1921 (Box 190, Folder 2336)
      - Monkey, n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2337)
      - "These fragrant roses please me well," by Diamond Jim (2), ca. 1923 (Box 190, Folder 2338-2339)
      - Toy base, figure missing, n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2340)
      - "When Simple Simon strolled by chance," by Diamond Jim, ca. 1922 (Box 190, Folder 2341)
      - [Whirling toy] (broken), n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2342)
    - Family Memorabilia
      Folder numbers are used as unique identification numbers only.
      - Baby shoe, bronzed, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2343)
      - Change purse and wallet, leather (Box 191, Folder 2344-2345)
      - Diptych, brass, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2346)
      - Fabrics
        - Braid or hat trim (2 pieces), n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2347)
        - Collar and cuffs designed and stencil painted by Peter Newell for Helen Newell, with cut paper patterns (Box 191, Folder 2348-2350)
        - Cuffs, lace (from Leona Newell's wedding dress?), ca. 1885 (Box 191, Folder 2351)
        - Dress fabric piece, silk, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2352)
        - Handkerchief, embroidered with flowers and "Paris 1900" (Box 191, Folder 2353)
        - Washcloth, sewn by Marcus Gordon, 1894 (Box 191, Folder 2354)
      - Fountain pen (Ideal), n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2355)
      - Head (of a mythological figure?), cast metal, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2356)
      - Jewelry
        - Brooch, carved and painted by Peter Newell, with bird motif (Box 191, Folder 2357)
        - Necklace, gold beads strung on cotton cord, from Ashcraft family, ca. 1880 (Box 191, Folder 2358)
        - Ring, silver, Southwestern U.S. or Mexico, horse motif, ca. 1910 (Box 191, Folder 2359)
        - Stickpin, metal with orange stone, ca. 1900 (Box 191, Folder 2360)
      - Napkin ring, sterling silver, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2361)
      - Painting supplies
        - Palettes (2) for oil paints, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2362-2363)
        - Paintbox, with cake watercolors, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2364)
        - Mixing tray, ceramic, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2365)
      - Picture frame, carved and painted wood by Peter Newell (Box 192, Folder 2366)
      - Picture frame, pocket miniature, with photo of Clendenon Newell (Box 192, Folder 2367)
      - Pipe, decorated by Merle Johnson, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2368)
      - Plaque, Chinese, wood and lacquer (Box 192, Folder 2369)
      - Pocket knife in sterling silver case, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2370)
      - Pocket watch, Hampden Watch Co. in Thiery watchcase, given to George F. Newell by Peter Newell, ca. 1880 (Box 192, Folder 2371)
      - Pocket watch, Waltham, case engraved with Marcus A. Gordon's initials, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2372)
      - Shell novelties from Paris Exposition (souvenirs for Newell daughters), 1900 (Box 192, Folder 2373-2374)
      - Sword guard, Japanese, iron and brass (Box 192, Folder 2375)
      - Hopi revival pottery, ca. 1910 (Box 193, Folder 2376-2377)
      - Hopi revival pottery, ca. 1910 (Box 194, Folder 2378-2379)
- Newell Family Photographs, 1865-1980; Series III; 7.6; (11 boxes)
  Series III. is composed of photographs and negatives owned by members of the Newell family. Pictures of Peter and Leona Newell and their three children are found in the first subseries, Immediate Family, filed chronologically under each person's name. Family Group Photographs and Family Homes follow. In addition, early photographs and tintypes of Newell, his family and some of his artwork can be found in the bound album in Box 196. In a second subseries, Extended Family and Friends, the pictures are arranged alphabetically by principal name. Smaller subseries of Leonia Society photos and Miscellaneous and Unidentified images are filed after. Glass Plate Negatives and Lantern Slides end the series. Flexible film negatives have been interfiled with the paper photographs.
  Images of Newell family members can also be found in the section of Leonia Society pictures.
  - IMMEDIATE FAMILY
    - Newell, Peter
      - Tintype portraits, ca. 1868-70 (Box 195, Folder 2380)
      - Portrait by Shreeves, Bushnell, ca. 1875 (Box 195, Folder 2381)
      - Tintype portrait, ca. 1876 (Box 195, Folder 2382)
      - Portrait by Clendenon and Nichols, Jacksonville, ca. 1878 (Box 195, Folder 2383)
      - Tintype portrait, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2384)
      - Portrait, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2385)
      - Portraits by Clendenon and Nichols, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2386)
      - Portrait of Newell as Oscar Wilde by Clendenon and Nichols, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2387)
      - Studio tableau photographs by Clendenon and Nichols, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2388)
      - Candid stereograph after ice storm by Clendenon and Nichols, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2389)
      - Candid photograph with Leona near Illinois College gate, Jacksonville, ca. 1880 (Box 195, Folder 2390)
      - Portrait by Parkinson, New York, ca. 1885 (Box 195, Folder 2391)
      - Candid and professional photographs made in during Colorado trip, including some by William E. Hook, 1887-88 (Box 195, Folder 2392)
      - Candid photographs, Chicago, 1889 (Box 195, Folder 2393)
      - Portrait by Peter A. Juley, New York, ca. 1890 (Box 195, Folder 2394)
      - Candid photograph outside home, Leonia, ca. 1895 (Box 195, Folder 2395)
      - Candid photograph with cello, Leonia, ca. 1895 (Box 195, Folder 2396)